

Julian Godon Senior Full Stack Developer

Email: juliango202@gmail.com - Tel: (+33)6 75 84 30 48

Github: https://github.com/juliango202

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/257272/julian-go

Codewars: https://www.codewars.com/users/juliango202

I'm looking for: a future-oriented company with a strong engineering culture

Profile

I'm a full stack developer with a deep experience covering a variety of languages and domains, and a passion for writing clean code. I started coding at 12 on the family 8086 computer, and I've been enjoying programming personal and professional projects ever since.

Some recent examples of my personal projects are TerrainVer(goo.gl/w6dwCH, Javascript), jijimaku(goo.gl/Mtt9We, Java 8), and memobuild(goo.gl/dfj8eG, Python, Javascript, Google App Engine). See my website https://juliango202.com for a full list including older projects in C++, OpenGL, Ruby, and more.

Recently I've been interested in the advances in AI and deep learning in particular, it's one of the domain I would love an opportunity to explore.

Experience

2014-Dec 2017: Senior Software Engineer, Axa(www.axa.com), Web & Innovation Dept. Axa is one of the world's largest insurance company.

- worked on proof of concepts projects: I developed a bulk document import script for Couchbase to assess database performance(NoSQL/Couchbase, Java, RxJava). I worked with another developer on a client search portal demo that required weekly iterations(.NET, Javascript). 90/100 at my annual performance review.
- asked to take over the development of an online subscription application with a risky reputation because of the major overhaul to do and the tight deadlines, I developed the changes by batches mostly alone and on schedule(.NET, Javascript, Bootstrap, SQL Server), resulting in the application being green-lighted for use by all Axa brokers and a 95/100 mark at my annual performance review.
- selected as one of the two core developers for a new top project: a REST API for company-wide document storage replacing legacy software. In particular I was in charge of API design, logging, and error handling. We delivered all the features(Java, Springboot, NoSQL, AWS), along with a demo SPA(ReactJS). I briefed a new recruit in late 2017 to replace me for future updates.

2009-2014: Software Engineer freelance, PopIn(http://www.popin.cc/)
PopIn is a Japanese start-up focused on online advertising and news services.

I was one of only four original engineers working with the CEO to develop Popin services, meaning everybody had to be versatile and autonomous. After years of growth, Popin was acquired in 2015 by Baidu in a multi-million dollar deal.

• I developed web applications for managing online ad campaigns, mostly alone and from scratch(PHP, MVC, MongoDB, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap).

• I used machine learning for automatic classification of news articles and products similarity measurements(Java, Mahout). To integrate with the Mahout library I developed a script(C, SQLite) that could read our logs and map our internal UUIDs to arbitrary integers quickly(~70K lines/second).

2009-2014: Entrepreneur, memobuild(http://www.memobuild.com/)

As a personal project I developed memobuild, an online collaborative editor for documents. While it failed to gain traction, I believe it's still a great example of a fully scalable web application(Google App Engine, Python, Javascript). Interestingly, I organized documents in "components" that each had some JavaScript "props" and a template that would be redrawn on prop change(this model recently became ubiquitous thanks to ReactJS).

2006-2008: Computer Graphics Engineer, GSports(http://gsport.co.jp/)

I was the company Computer Graphics expert and worked on 3D rendering(C+++, OpenGL), object tracking(C+++, OpenCV), and more. In particular I wrote a method to draw 3D muscles using vertex buffers that resulted in a 50x performance increase.

Technical skills

• First I want to mention that I just completed an online course on Deep Learning (from Prof. Andrew Ng at Coursera), and I have plenty of experience with related technologies:

Python, Image processing, GPGPU, and Machine Learning.

• Here is what I used recently and I'm experienced in:

Languages:	Python, Java, Javascript, Html5
Databases:	SQL, NoSQL(Marklogic, Couchbase, Google Datastore)
DevOps:	AWS, GCP, Jenkins, Git, Linux, Shell
Design:	MVC frameworks, Error handling, Scalability

- I haven't used recently but I have several years of experience with: C, C++, Ruby, Computer Graphics (OpenGL)
- I've used occasionally and given some catch-up time I can work with:

 Machine Learning (Mahout), GPGPU, 3D Algorithms (Octrees, Nurbs,...), Vision and

 Augmented reality (OpenCV), Matlab, Functional programming (OCaml)

Education

2005: Research semester at the University of Tokyo — Japan

2003: Exchange student at UNC Chapel Hill - USA (GPA:3.5/4)

2000-2005: Master in Computer Sciences, Computer Graphics specialization,

University of Toulouse - France

Other interests

Beside programming I like discovering foreign cultures, I've lived one year in the United States and eight years in Japan. I speak English fluently and I'm fully proficient in Japanese.